- Think about a project you're working on right now.
-想想一下您現在正在處理的項目。
Ever felt like you've gone through
有沒有覺得自己以前經歷過
the exact same motions before?
完全相同的動作嗎？
I'm here to show you another way.
我在這裡向你展示另一種方法。
And this method will not just help you
此方法不僅將幫助您完
with your current project,
成當前項目，
but it will also set you up with a custom AI tool
而且還將為您設置一個自定義 AI 工具
that you can go back to time and time again.
，您可以一次又一次回去。
Sounds cool but also complicated?
聽起來很酷，但也很複雜？
It's not.
不是
I'm Ammaar.
我是阿瑪爾。
I lead Product & Design on Google AI Studio,
我在 Google AI 工
the platform where you can work
作室領導產品與設計，這是您可以使用
with the latest Google models
最新的 Google 模型並構
and build your ideas.
建構想法的平台。
And AI has been a game changer
而 AI 一直是讓我的想法變
for bringing my ideas to life.
成現實的改變者。
From books, animated shorts, coding games,
從書籍、動畫短片、編碼遊戲
podcasts with people from the past, and more,
、帶有過去人的播客等等，
AI has unleashed my creativity.
AI 釋放了我的創造力。
Throughout your learning journey,
在整個學習過程中，
you've been collaborating with AI to amplify your skills.
您一直與 AI 合作，以擴大您的技能。
You can work with AI to brainstorm ideas,
您可以與 AI 合作，以腦力激發想法、
draft tailored communications,
草擬量身定制的通訊，
or get a first pass on a status report.
或獲得狀態報告的第一次通知。
You're having a conversation with AI
您正在與 AI 進行對話
to solve the challenge right in front of you.
，以解決正面前面的挑戰。
Now, let's zoom out and make even bigger strides.
現在，讓我們縮小並取得更大的步伐。
Across all of your work,
在您所有工作中，
what are the challenges you are encountering
您一次又一
time and time again?
次遇到的挑戰是什麼？
You might think to yourself,
您可能會對自己想：
"I wish there was an app for this."
「我希望有一個應用程序適用於此。」
Well, in this course,
好吧，在這個課
you're going to learn how to build it
程中，您將學習如何構建
so that the next time you come up against that challenge,
它，以便下次遇到挑戰時，
you have a way to solve it fast.
您有一種快速解決它的方法。
You're going to learn to create custom shareable apps
您將學習使用為您設計的
using AI that are designed by you for you.
AI 創建自定義可共享應用程序。
And this is the next step in your AI journey,
這是您的 AI 旅程中的下一步，從成為 AI 的
moving from being a user of AI
用戶轉為成為自
to becoming a builder of your own AI-powered solutions.
己的 AI 驅動解決方案的建構者。
To do so, I'm going to introduce you
為此，我將向您介紹一個叫
to something called vibe coding.
做 vibe 編碼的東西。
It's a way you can use natural language
這是您可以使用自然語言使用
to build software or apps with AI.
AI 構建軟件或應用程序的一種方式。
You can then use that app
然後，您可以使用該應
to make it easier to get stuff done.
用程序來更輕鬆地完成工作。
For example, let's say you have this kind of annoying task
例如，假設您總是必須執行這種煩人的
you always have to do,
任務，例如為每
like resizing images for your monthly newsletter.
月通訊的圖像調整大小。
You wish you had an app with a big Upload button
您希望您有一個帶有一個大上傳按鈕
that you could drop the images into
的應用程序，您可以將圖像放
and instantly get them back in the size and format you need.
到中，並立即以所需的大小和格式恢復它們。
You'd also love for that app
您也希望該應用程序
to automatically rename the image files
自動重命名圖像文件
so that it follows your team's naming conventions.
，以便遵循團隊的命名慣例。
Well, with vibe coding,
好吧，通過 vibe 編碼，
you can build an app to do all of those things
您可以構建一個應用程序，以按照您需要的
just the way you need it.
方式完成所有這些事情。
Vibe coding is a lot like prompting,
Vibe 編碼很像提示，它要求您準確
it requires you to describe exactly what you need,
描述所需的內容，提
give AI details about your workflow,
供有關您的工作流程的 AI 詳細信息，並幫
and help it understand good results from bad ones.
助它理解壞結果和不好的結果。
It can then attempt to create your dream app.
然後它可以嘗試創建您的夢想應用程序。
But how is this even possible?
但是這怎麼可能？
Well, when you vibe code,
好吧，當您調整編碼時，
you're actually using something called agentic AI,
您實際上使用稱為代理人工智能的東西，
and this type of AI
而這種類型的 AI 不僅
goes beyond just responding to your prompts.
僅僅僅是響應您的提示。
It takes action on your behalf,
它代表您採取行動，
but only under your supervision, of course.
但當然只在您的監督下。
After you describe what you need
在您
using normal, non-technical words,
使用正常的非技術單詞描述所需的內容後，
agentic AI handles all the techy stuff
agentic AI 會處理所有技術的事情，例
like writing code,
如編寫代碼，構
building the interface,
建界面以及確保所有
and making sure everything works together.
內容一起運作。
And in this course,
在本課程中，
you'll learn how to vibe code
您將學習如何調整程式碼
to tackle some of the challenges you face at work.
來解決您在工作中面臨的一些挑戰。
First, you'll map out your personal workflow
首先，您將制定個人工作流程，
and pinpoint exactly where a custom app
並準確地確定自定義應用程序可
would help you save the most time.
幫助您節省最多時間的位置。
Next, you'll see vibe coding in action.
接下來，您將看到 vibe 編碼正在執行中。
I'll walk you through different examples
我將向您介紹不同的例子，
so you can see how it works from start to finish.
以便您可以從頭到尾看到它是如何運作的。
Finally, you'll build your own app.
最後，您將構建自己的應用程序。
I'll guide you step by step
我將逐步指導您，
and make sure you know how to vibe code responsibly
並確保您知道如何負責任地調整程式碼
and troubleshoot common issues.
並解決常見問題。
You'll find out how to evaluate the code AI developed,
您將了解如何評估 AI 開發的代碼、擁有結
own the results,
果並隨著時
and maintain your app over time.
間的推移維護您的應用程序。
All of this will help make sure
所有這些都將有助於確保
you create an app that actually works.
您創建一個實際有效的應用程序。
And by the end of the course,
在課程結束時，
you'll have a method you can repeatedly use
您將有一種可以重複使用的方法來
to identify ways Gemini, Google AI Studio and NotebookLM
識別 Gemini、Google AI Studio 和 NotebookLM
can help you in your job,
可以幫助您完成工作的方法，
and you'll have the skills and confidence you need
並且您將擁有創
to create a custom app
建一個可以
that can handle some of your larger tasks.
處理一些更大的任務的自定義應用程序所需的技能和信心。
If you're ready to start building,
如果您準備好開始構建，
let's jump in.
讓我們進行。